A Guide to the Gertrude E. Perlmann papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA189
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1944-1974
  - Sm-Sz (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Szuchet, Sara, 12 items
      Includes Szuchet et al reprints.
  - T-Tö (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Tabor, Herbert, 3 items
    - Taborsky, George, 1961-1973; 15 items
      Includes correspondence. about phosvitin work.
    - Tanford, Charles, 1 item
    - Tang, Jordan J.N., 1961-1973; 27 items
    - Tanksley, T.D., 2 items
    - Tata, J.R., 2 items
    - Thayssen, J. Hess, 1 item
    - Thompson, Thomas E. About York Tsang, 8 items
    - Tiffany, Lois. About phosvitin work, 4 items
    - Timasheff (Gorbunoff), Marina. AAUW and NIH research fellowship recommendations, 6 items
    - Timasheff, S.N., 1966-1974; 13 items
    - Tondo, Casemiro V., 3 items
    - Toralballa, Gloria, 6 items
    - Townend, R., 1 item
  - Tr-Tu (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Traub, Wolfie, 26 items
    - Traymore Hotel, 1 item
    - Trop, Moshe. Staff appointment, 22 items
    - Tsang, C. Mr. and Mrs. About York Tsang, 2 items
    - Tsang, York, 1963-1965 1973; 34 items
      Includes staff appointment; photocopied typescript of Thompson and Tsang 1963 ACS meeting presentation; recommendation for.
    - Tschoegl, N.W., 2 items
    - Turnbull, J.H., 9 items
      Includes Turnbull curriculum vitae; Turnbull et al reprints.
  - V-von (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Vandendriesche, L., 3 items
    - Van Vunakis, Helen, 1963 February 27 1967 June 12; 21 items
      Includes 1963 Feb. 27, 1967 June 12 Brandeis Univ. seminars; about pepsinogen work.
    - Varma, R., 2 items
    - Vennesland, Birgit, 1961-1974; 17 items
    - Vidali, Giorgio, 35 items
      Includes biographical material; letters of recommendation from Perlmann, Luck, Zinder and others; Vidali et al reprints.
    - Villafranca, Joseph, 5 items
    - von Hippel, Peter, 1961-1968; 9 items
  - W (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Wacker, Warren E.C., 2 items
    - Walton, Alan G. About Biopolymer Subgroup of Biophysical Society, 5 items
      Includes By-Laws and membership list (Dr. Perlmann member).
    - Weaver, Edwin S., 2 items
    - Weinstein, Boris, 1 item
    - Weisiger, James R., 2 items
    - Weisskopf, Victor, 1 item
    - Wetlaufer, Don B., 2 items
    - White, Abraham, 1 item
      On hostessing C.B. Anfinsen party after his Harvey Lecture at RU.
    - White, Thomas T., 2 items
    - Wikler, Maurice, 4 items
    - Wilcox, P.E., 1 item
    - Wildi, Bernard S., 2 items
    - Williams, Curtis A. Curriculum vitae, 1 item
    - Wilson, D.
      (See under: Albertson, Donna correspondence. Box no. 4).
    - Wilson, T. curriculum vitae, 1 item
    - Wittliff, James L., 2 items
    - Woerner, Lee. Refreshments for party, 1970 June 23; 1 item
    - Wolff, Edith C., 3 items
    - Wolstenholme, G.E.W., 1 item
    - Woodfin, Beulah, 2 items
    - Wong, Rosie C., 1968-1971; 39 items
      Includes: staff appointment; recommendations for.
    - Woods Hole. Marine Biological Laboratory, 3 items
    - Woods, Frank, 2 items
    - Work, T.S. Item on Oxford Biochemical Society meeting, 1963 July 16-31; 4 items
    - Worthington Biochemical Corp., 1 item
    - Wriston, John C., 2 items
    - Wyman, J., 3 items
  - Y-Z (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Yang, D.N., 1 item
    - Yang, Jen Tsl (Frank), 1963-1973; 15 items
    - Yaron, Arieh, 3 items
    - Yasunobu, Kerry T., 2 items
    - Yon, Jeanine, 3 items
    - Young, D.E., 1 item
    - York, Marcetta, 1 item
    - Yphantis, David, 4 items
      Includes curriculum vitae; American Society of Biological Chemists membership recommendation.
    - Zaccarias, A.V., 2 items
    - Zamoyska, Bradley A., 1 item
    - Zeuthen, Eric, 2 items
    - Zimm, Bruno H., 1 item
    - Zito, Romano, 1 item
    - Zuber, H., 2 items
- Rockefeller University Administration Subject Files
  For the University administration G.E. Perlmann worked with students in planning courses, conducting interviews, and planning lectures. Also included is correspondence with the administration on laboratory personnel, budgeting and grant applications.
  Arrangement is by subject and approximate chronological order.
  - Administrative correspondence
    Arranged in approximate chronological order.
    - Miscellaneous, 1945-1956; 17 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence with A.R. Dochez; E.B. Smith; V. du Vigneaud, Petrzelka, Cogger about appointments, salary, retirement, group Life Insurance, Blue Cross, laboratory matter.
    - Gasser, Herbert, 1947-1953; 11 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Scientific staff appointments; Carlsberg laboratory visit.
    - RI Staff Meetings, 1951-1952; 19 items (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Perlmann, Secretary of the Program Committee.
    - Rivers, Thomas M., 1953-1955; 4 items (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Visit to Carlsberg and Fromageot's laboratories; NSF travel award.
    - Flinn, Waldo R. and Whitaker, Douglas, 1956-1964; 58 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Expenditures of laboratory funds including travel: laboratory appointments.
    - Bronk, Detlev W., 1954-1971; 68 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Includes holograph; letter of commendation for Perlmann RU lecture.
    - Campbell, Charles I., 1957-1961; 17 items (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Primarily information for Quarterly Review.
    - Seitz, Frederick, 1968-1974; 76 items (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Assorted correspondence. but includes listing of current status of former Perlmann post-docs and various recommendations.
    - Gold, Albert, 1969-1973; 7 items (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Dean's Office (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Correspondence with Brink, Frank and Hirsch, James deals primarily with student courses.
  - Student Interviews (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Interviews and evaluations of prospective students to RU graduate program:.
    Ballard, Stephen G.
    Hunkapiller, Michael.
    Leavitt, Randi Y.
    Nash, Barbara T.
    Richmond, Timothy J.
    Arrangement alphabetical and then chronological within each student.
  - Students, 2 folders
    Dr. Perlmann committee chairman to evaluate student theses and conduct final examinations for some students and for others functioned as part of faculty committees for examination, tutorial and progress reports and for grant and fellowship recommendations. Served as outside examiner for thesis evaluation of Sila Chaudhuri (student from India).
    Arrangement alphabetical and then chronological within each folder.
    - Bennett, Gudrun (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Burgess, Paul R. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Cellarius, Richard A. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Chaudhuri, Shila (Calcutta University) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Englund, Paul T. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Fruchter, Rachel G. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Iwanij, Victoria (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Kent, Joan L. (Box 10, Folder 12)
      (See also under: Purple, Richard in Box no. 10, folder 13).
    - Laiken, Nora D. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Laiken, Stuart (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Purple, Richard (Box 10, Folder 13)
      (See also under: Kent, Joan Box 10, folder 12).
    - Rossomando, Edward P. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Schwartz, James H. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Simon, Sanford (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Yip, Cecil C. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Student teaching, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    G.E. Perlmann, D. Mauzerall, G. Edelman taught Physical Chemistry course.
    Includes handwritten corrections by G.E. Perlmann for RU catalog.
  - Student Course notes in Biochemistry and Protein Chemistry. Plan for student courses with outline. Pages numbered consecutively as found, 1955-1957 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Student Courses sponsored and organized by G.E. Perlmann
    - ORD-CD Course, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Correspondence; typescript draft on notes on [Harrington?] lecture; purchase orders for course equipment; bibliography; working material; some student submitted material (curves and measurements).
    - ORD-CD Courses: Correspondence; bibliographies; working material, 1969 1970 1972 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - W.F. Harrington course (8 lectures) "Association Behavior of Proteins", 1974 January (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Correspondence; bibliography; working material includes notes.
      (See also under: Harrington, W.F. correspondence. Box no. 5).
    - ORD-CD course, 1974 February-March (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Correspondence; bibliographies; working material; includes Review by Stryer and Critical Review in Biochemistry by Strickland.
  - Lecture Committee, 1967-1969 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Lectures: RU faculty committee on lectures. Correspondence; lecture arrangements; some duplicated material.
  - Faculty and Student Club, 1967-1970 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    On Board of Directors. Primarily duplicated material.
  - University Senate (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Primarily duplicated material; includes minutes of meetings.
  - General Notices/Reports, 1969-1973 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Primarily duplicated material.
    - Summary. Survey on status of RU Academic Personnel, 1971-1972
    - Christiania Leonard (Asst. Prof. RU) Report "An inquiry into the status of women in science", 1973
  - Laboratory (Box 11)
    - Laboratory Budgets, 1959-1960 - 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Includes some correspondence; proposals; budgets and revisions.
    - Laboratory Efforts; Time Reports (Time spent on various activities) (Box 11, Folder 11)
      Includes.
      - Marie Chiao, 1972-1973
      - Dolores Madonia, 1973-1974
      - Uri Marchaim, 1974
      - Gertrude E. Perlmann, 1967-1974
    - Laboratory plans and equipment, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      Includes original laboratory plans (correspondence., architects drawings, working material) for Perlmann laboratory; items concerning equipment; requisitions; 1971 hazardous chemical inventory; plans for various lab installations.
    - Laboratory personnel miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Correspondence with personnel, accounting depts.
      Deals primarily with salaries and allocations; vacations.
    - Laboratory Personnel, 1953-1974; 4 folders (Box 12)
      Staff and technician job Inquiries; applications; technician appointments and recommendations for.
      Arrangement in alphabetical order.
      - A-C (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - D-H (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - I-M (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - N-Z (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Travel
    - Correspondence primarily with hotels; travel vouchers (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Grants (Miscellaneous) (Box 12, Folder 7)
      Miscellaneous items concerning grants.
      Includes Mary J. Mycek USPH Fellowship.
    - Grants awarded for scientific research and travel
      Correspondence; applications; award notices; progress reports; duplicated material; few denials included.
      Arranged in chronological order within each institution.
      - NIH, 1956-1959 (Box 13, Folder 1)
        Includes L.G. Longsworth handwritten recommendation for Perlmann research grant award.
      - NIH, 1958-1963 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - NIH, 1964-1969 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - NIH, 1969-1974 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - NSF Travel Grants, 1955-1960 (Box 13, Folder 5)
        To attend various meetings and laboratories abroad.
      - NSF, 1961-1968 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - NSF, 1969-1974 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Research Corp, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - American Cancer Society, 1970-1973 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Fellowship; grant applications denied, 1968 1973 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Laboratory reports
    Laboratory reports of workers other than G.E. Perlmann.
    Reports; mss; laboratory notes.
    Includes reports of work on pepsin-pepsinogen; phosvitin etc. carried on in Perlmann laboratory by individual workers and visitors. Some merely lab notes of incomplete work. Pages numbered consecutively as found.
    Arrangement in alphabetical order by worker.
    - Albertson, Donna, 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Typescript of summer work; chromatograms of work done at Mt. Holyoke; correspondence.
    - Allerton, Sam - Phosvitin. Typescript reporting work on phosvitin, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - [Chiao, Marie] - Phosvitin Typescripts of experimental procedures and results, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Includes handwritten notes.
    - Finlay, Tom, 1972-1973
      Includes material provided for Perlmann 1972 Annual Report; typescript drafts with corrections of mss and possible talks; working material; correspondence. In 2 folders.
      - pp. 1-144 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - pp. 145-262 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Gaskin, Felicia - Phosvitin, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Typescripts of experimental work and procedures; includes material provided for Perlmann Annual Report; correspondence; graphs.
    - Grizzuti, Kart - Phosvitin, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Typescript of material provided for Perlmann Annual Report; correspondence (some from Lisa[?]) includes experimental work; graphs; charts.
    - [Harrington], Bill - Pepsin-Inhibitor, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Typescripts of experimental work and procedures; graphs; working material; 1 holograph (correspondence) signed Bill [Take this to be Bill Harrington?].
    - Hartley, Brian Pepsinogen-Pepsin, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
      Perlmann handwritten outline of discussion with Brian Hartley at International Congress of Biochemistry.
    - Jane [last name not known] - Phosvitin, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      Typescript of experimental work and procedures; includes laboratory notes; graphs chromatograms.
    - Marchaim, Uri - Phosphoproteins, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      Typescript of experimental work and presentation.
      Includes tables; graphs; working material; handwritten note.
    - Muller-Eberhard, Ursula (from Scripps Clinic, La Jolla, Calif.) - ORD-CD, 1969-1970
      Includes calculations and experiments done in laboratory for Dr. Muller-Eberhard; includes typescripts of Muller-Eberhard paper and abstract; figures. In 2 folders.
      - pp. 1-80 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - pp. 81-167 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Nakagawa, Y. - Pepsin-Pepsinogen, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Typescript of experimental work and possible presentation.
      Includes graphs; tables.
    - Oestreicher, B.A.- Pepsin-Pepsinogen, 1962-1963 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Typescript of experimental work and procedures.
      Includes graphs; lab notes; measurements; experimental work outline.
    - Shainkin, Ruth - Peptide; phosvitin, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Various typescript reports on experimental work.
      Includes lab notes; graphs; tables; published papers by others.
    - Tsang, York - Trypsin experiments, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Typescripts of report on experimental work.
      Includes figures; tables; procedures; graphs; lab notes.
    - Van Vunakis, H.- Pepsinogen-Immun, 1960-1961 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Reports by Dr. Van Vunakis students at Brandeis on procedures developed in Perlmann lab.
      Includes preparations; procedures; laboratory notes; Van Vunakis progress report; gel diffusion photographs; reprint and mss by others.
    - Wong, Rosie - Porcine pepsinogen, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Handwritten summary of experimental work; 1 item correspondence.
- Reviews Manuscripts/Grant Proposals
  Dr. Perlmann served as reviewer for scientific journals and for institutions on grant requests.
  Includes one complete ms; most grant proposals.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by journal or institution. In chronological order within each folder.
  - Mss. Reviews
    - Analytical Biochemistry, 1966-1973 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Archives of Biochemistry and Biophysics, 1953-1970 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Biochemistry, 1962 1967-1974 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Canadian J. of Chemistry, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Immunochemistry, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - J. American Chemical Society, 1955-1961 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - J. Biological Chemistry, 1959 1963 1966 1972 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      Includes S. Moore handwritten comments on Folsch and Osterberg ms.
    - J. Biophys. Biochem. Cytol., 1956, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - J. Clinical Investigation, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - J. General Physiology; [nd], 1958 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Nature, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Science, 1968-1970 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Grant proposals
    - American Philosophical Society, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - NIH, 1954 1958 1959 1961 1970 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - NSF, 1957 1958 1964 1965 1970 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - NSF, 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - NSF, 1972 1974 (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Conferences; meetings; seminars, 1949-1974
  Consists of correspondence; programs; memorabilia; mss with working materials; outlines; abstracts; some cancellations. In some instances information is sketchy and inconclusive. An active participant in Gordon Conferences and includes many group photographs with identification.
  - Detroit meeting, 1949 April 19 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Typescript "of the effect of lithium on crystalline bovine serum albumin".
    [Editor's note: This typescript found in folder with Goebel/Perlmann ms. published in J. Exp. Med. 89 (1949) 479-489].
  - RIMR Staff Meeting, 1949 May 20 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Typescript "on ovalbumin"; background information of calculations supplied by K. Linderstrøm-Lang.
  - Cambridge, Mass. Harvard Medical School, Department of Physical Chemistry talk, 1949 November 14 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Typescript "enzymatic modifications of ovalbumin".
  - NY City 1st Macy Foundation, 1950 April 24, 25 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Conference on Connective Tissues Diseases. Typescript "Enzymatically modified ovalbumins" with discussion and correspondence. Published in 1951. See #21 in bibliography.
  - Copenhagen, Denmark, 18th International Physiological Congress, 1950 August (Box 17, Folder 5)
    Typescript "An electrophoretic study of dephosphorylated ovalbumins". Abstract published 1950. See #20a in bibliography.
  - Boston, Mass. 119th American Chemical Society Symposium, 1951 April (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Typescript "A study of the phosphorus linkages in ovalbumin and plakalbumin". Abstract published 1951. See #21a in bibliography.
  - NY City RIMR Staff Meeting, 1951 May 25 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Typescript "Dephosphorylated ovalbumin".
  - Pratt Institute, Second Symposium on Phosphorus Metabolism, 1952 June 16-19 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Typescript "Enzymatic dephosphorylation of phosphoproteins and the nature of the phosphorus linkages". with figures and correspondence. Published in 1952. See #28 in bibliography.
  - Paris, France 2nd International Congress of Biochemistry, 1952 July 21-27 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Typescript of abstract "Enzymatic dephosphorylation of phosphoproteins" with correspondence. and printed Congress information. Abstract published in 1952. See #23a in bibliography.
  - Cambridge University. The Faraday Society Symposium on "The Physical Chemistry of Proteins", 1952 August 6-8 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    Typescript "Electrophoretic studies on enzymatically modified ovalbumin and casein" with correspondence; figures; plans of Cambridge. Published in 1953. See #30 in bibliography.
  - Laconia, NH Gordon Conferences of AAAS on Proteins and Nucleic Acids, 1953 August 23-28 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    Group photograph of participants with photo identification.
  - RU Staff Meeting presentation, 1954 October 22 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    Typescript "Phosphoproteins" with handwritten outline; photographs of figures.
  - Gatlinburg, Tenn. Oal Ridge Nat'l Laboratories, Biology Division, 8th Annual Biology Research Conference on Enzyme and Protein Structure, 1955 April 4-6 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    Participates as a discussant with Fritz Lipmann in Apr. 6 Conference on Interaction of enzymes, coenzymes and substrates.
    Correspondence with map of Oak Ridge and vicinity; Gatlinburg brochure; handwritten expenses.
  - Brussels, Belgium, 3rd International Congress Biochemistry, 1955 August 1-6 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    Typescripts "The phosphorus linkage in pepsin" and abstract with correspondence; general information Congress booklet. Abstract published in 1955.
    See #36a in bibliography.
  - Oxford University, The Faraday Society Symposium on "The Physical Chemistry of the Enzymes", 1955 August 10-12 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    [Indications Perlmann attends but no evidence of presentation].
    Correspondence with plans of Oxford.
  - New Hampton, NH Gordon Research Conferences on Proteins and Nucleic Acids, 1957 June 30-July 5 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    Perlmann presentation July 3 "Observations on pepsin".
    Includes duplicated material on: general information, programs, list of participants; correspondence with group photograph of participants with photo identification.
  - Paris, France, International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry (IUPAC) Symposium on protein structure, 1957 July 25-29 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    Typescript of Perlmann and Mycek paper "Modification of pepsin by autodigestion". Published in 1958 in Symposium on Protein Structure edited by Albert Neuberger. See #40 in bibliography. G.E. Perlmann not listed on program but includes typescript of contribution to discussion "Partial inactivation of pepsin by selective enzymes".
    Includes programs; correspondence; photocopied symposium background material.
  - South Hadley, Mass. Mount Holyoke College lecture, 1957 November 20 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    Typescript "Proteins" and handwritten outline of lecture with slide outline.
  - Stockholm, Sweden International Congress for Microbiology, 1958 August 4-8 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    Correspondence.
  - Vienna, IV International Congress of Biochemistry, Symposium VIII "Proteins", 1958 September 1-6 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    Typescript "Optical rotation and enzyme activity of pepsin"; with correspondence; tables; photographs taken at Symposium with negatives.
  - Philadelphia, Pa. Federation meeting, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    [No indication Perlmann attends].
    Typescript of Blumenfeld presentation "Differential ultraviolet spectra of pepsin".
  - Gatlinburg, Tenn. 12th Annual Research Conference sponsored by Biology Division of the Oak Ridge Nat'l Laboratory on "Enzyme Reaction Mechanisms" [Indications Perlmann attends but no evidence of presentation], 1959 April 1-4 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    Correspondence; photograph taken at what appears to be evening function of Conference includes identification; booklet on general information and program.
  - New Hampton, NH Gordon Research Conferences on Proteins and Nucleic Acids, 1959 June 29-July 3 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    Perlmann participates in July 2 session discussion on Hydration and denaturation.
    Typescript of Blumenfeld presentation in same discussion "The action of unfolding agents on pepsin".
    Includes general information; program; group photograph of participants with identification.
  - Stockholm 1st IUB/IUBS Joint Symposium on "Biological Structure and Function", 1960 September 12-17 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    Typescript draft "The relation of secondary structure of pepsin to its biological activity".
    Includes program; correspondence; figures; corrected galley proof.
    Published in 1961. See #48 in bibliography.
  - NY City RI Staff Meeting presentation, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    Typescript "current laboratory work on pepsin".
  - St. Louis, Mo. Biophysical Society meeting, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    Typescripts of Perlmann and E. Katchalski "Configuration of poly-l-methionine and its derivitives in solution" and abstract.
    Includes correspondence; background material. Abstract published in 1961. See #50a in bibliography.
  - NY City Iota Sigma Pi, Columbian chapter annual luncheon, 1961 May 6 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    Correspondence indicates Perlmann guest speaker.
  - Madison, Wisconsin. Poly-α-Amino Acid Symposium, 1961 June 19-23 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    [Indications are Dr. Perlmann attends but no presentation].
    Includes program; correspondence.